<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00008148">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2010-12-08T14:18:13</Created>
	<LastChange>2011-09-09T10:46:58</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00008148.tif" imageWidth="3584" imageHeight="4608">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<UnorderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<OrderedGroup id="r61">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r43" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r45" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r46" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r48" index="3"/></OrderedGroup>
	<OrderedGroup id="r62">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r50" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r51" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r52" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r54" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r55" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r56" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r57" index="6"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r58" index="7"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r60" index="8"/></OrderedGroup></UnorderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r41" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="3020" y="320"/>
	<Point x="3020" y="375"/>
	<Point x="2928" y="374"/>
	<Point x="2928" y="320"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>585</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r42">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="717" y="353"/>
	<Point x="764" y="351"/>
	<Point x="888" y="348"/>
	<Point x="1027" y="345"/>
	<Point x="1333" y="345"/>
	<Point x="1534" y="342"/>
	<Point x="1836" y="351"/>
	<Point x="1946" y="357"/>
	<Point x="2029" y="359"/>
	<Point x="2196" y="358"/>
	<Point x="2225" y="357"/>
	<Point x="2418" y="359"/>
	<Point x="2597" y="367"/>
	<Point x="2773" y="378"/>
	<Point x="3015" y="386"/>
	<Point x="3011" y="412"/>
	<Point x="2970" y="412"/>
	<Point x="2837" y="407"/>
	<Point x="2754" y="401"/>
	<Point x="2643" y="393"/>
	<Point x="2371" y="383"/>
	<Point x="2024" y="380"/>
	<Point x="1723" y="370"/>
	<Point x="1446" y="367"/>
	<Point x="1246" y="367"/>
	<Point x="1038" y="368"/>
	<Point x="904" y="368"/>
	<Point x="718" y="378"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r43" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="709" y="401"/>
	<Point x="836" y="389"/>
	<Point x="943" y="383"/>
	<Point x="1279" y="384"/>
	<Point x="1468" y="384"/>
	<Point x="1469" y="397"/>
	<Point x="1468" y="441"/>
	<Point x="1465" y="710"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="980"/>
	<Point x="1464" y="986"/>
	<Point x="1464" y="997"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="1006"/>
	<Point x="1457" y="1070"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="1076"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="1081"/>
	<Point x="1458" y="1087"/>
	<Point x="1458" y="1141"/>
	<Point x="1457" y="1220"/>
	<Point x="1460" y="1230"/>
	<Point x="1459" y="1236"/>
	<Point x="1452" y="1463"/>
	<Point x="1455" y="1471"/>
	<Point x="1455" y="1476"/>
	<Point x="1452" y="1483"/>
	<Point x="1448" y="1729"/>
	<Point x="1450" y="1740"/>
	<Point x="1450" y="1748"/>
	<Point x="1448" y="1752"/>
	<Point x="1444" y="1940"/>
	<Point x="1446" y="1946"/>
	<Point x="1446" y="1955"/>
	<Point x="1444" y="1959"/>
	<Point x="1441" y="2210"/>
	<Point x="1439" y="2233"/>
	<Point x="1436" y="2262"/>
	<Point x="1438" y="2284"/>
	<Point x="1435" y="2301"/>
	<Point x="1437" y="2351"/>
	<Point x="1439" y="2357"/>
	<Point x="1437" y="2440"/>
	<Point x="1438" y="2447"/>
	<Point x="1438" y="2454"/>
	<Point x="1427" y="2768"/>
	<Point x="1425" y="2907"/>
	<Point x="1423" y="3186"/>
	<Point x="1414" y="3611"/>
	<Point x="1414" y="3844"/>
	<Point x="1411" y="3849"/>
	<Point x="1410" y="3885"/>
	<Point x="1410" y="3904"/>
	<Point x="1405" y="4084"/>
	<Point x="1402" y="4232"/>
	<Point x="1259" y="4231"/>
	<Point x="1249" y="4237"/>
	<Point x="1072" y="4235"/>
	<Point x="984" y="4227"/>
	<Point x="674" y="4214"/>
	<Point x="665" y="4220"/>
	<Point x="649" y="4220"/>
	<Point x="656" y="3932"/>
	<Point x="665" y="3417"/>
	<Point x="672" y="2867"/>
	<Point x="679" y="2445"/>
	<Point x="692" y="1753"/>
	<Point x="702" y="1196"/>
	<Point x="715" y="502"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>amongst you, I know, are honest and sincere men, for
whose characters I entertain unfeigned respect. Between
your opinions and mine the practical diﬀerence has always
seemed to me to be of small amount ; I have, therefore,
from the beginning of this contest deeply regretted the
division that exists between us. (Hear, hear.) I wished
that our united forces should do battle to the common
enemy. I oﬀered to agree to any fair compromise. I pro‑
mised to retire from the ﬁeld if I were the weaker, and to
give all the assistance in my power to your candidate.
These oﬀers your candidate rejected, and the contest went
on. Still I hoped that no angry feelings would arise be‑
tween us. I trusted we should abstain from personalities
towards each other, and that this would be a calm contest
of reason. In these my hopes I have been disappointed,
and for that disappointment I am not to blame. Not one
word of disrespect—not one syllable of reproach did I utter
against your candidate until I was assailed. When struck,
however, I am ever ready to strike in return. Who struck
the ﬁrst blow ? You, Mr. Miall ! You quitted the high
ground of argument. You descended into the arena of
abuse. You accused me of dishonesty on account of my
opinions with regard to Maynooth. You taxed me with in‑
sincerity because I possessed property in the Church of
England ; you called upon the Dissenters of Southwark to
shrink with horror from my opinions ; you attempted to
excite religious animosity and rancour against me ; like an
inquisitor of old, you presume to question me on my re‑
ligious belief, and to summon me before the tribunal of
your private judgment. I am glad to meet you here to‑
day, face to face, to answer you, to scoﬀ at your pretensions,
and to bid you deﬁance. I tell you, in the name of re‑
ligious liberty and equality, that no man has a right to
interfere with the religious opinions of another man ; that
no man has a right to question or blame the belief of his
neighbour. I tell you that in your conduct and language
towards me you have been untrue to the great principle of
religious liberty—you have been without that charity which
is the essence of religious liberty. You have denounced me
as the editor of the works of Hobbes of Malmesbury.
Electors, I am proud of the fact I will rest upon it a
claim to your support, in opposition to the claim of Mr.
Miall. He is the editor of the ‘ Nonconformist.' I am the
editor of Hobbes. To compare the two works together
would be like comparing the vastest mountain on the
earth's surface with the smallest mole‐hill. The works of
Hobbes will last more centuries than the ‘ Nonconformist'
will days. The writings of Hobbes will live as long as the
Anglo‐Saxon race and language. They will be read age
after age by the studious amongst the millions of our race
who will people the two Americas and the islands of the
Southern Ocean, and who will wonder at the ignorant and
bigoted herd who dared to assail so great a master of
thought and language. As one of that herd, Mr. Miall, it
is your only chance of escaping oblivion. When I com‑
menced this contest I was told by one of Mr Miall's ad‑
mirers thas he was a retired accomplished student, skilled
in literature, a lover of learning and wisdom, an acute rea‑
soner, an able writer, and in every way well ﬁtted to in‑
struct the nation through the public press. I did believe
all this, and I felt almost ashamed of entering into a con‑
test with such a person. Now, I ask you, electors, has
Mr Miall's conduct with regard to Hobbes been in con‑
formity with the character I have just given ? If you, Mr
Miall, had any love of learning, any regard for the litera‑
ture of your country, any reverence for the wisdom of past
times, any admiration for beauty of language, vigour of
expression, vigour of logic, and boldness of reasoning,
though you might, like myself, deem many of Hobbe's
opinions erroneous, though you might reject the whole of
his doctrines, yet you would have accorded praise, not
blame, to me for enabling the student to peruse the works
of one of England's most illustrious authors. No, like that
Mahometan warrior and bigot, who destroyed the wisdom
of ages, you would burn every work, and consume all lite‑
rature that in the slightest degree was at variance with
your limited notions—with your own Koran. You have
denounced me as the editor of an inﬁdel work ; I have
challenged you, and again challenge you, to make good
your assertions. I have called upon you to point out one
inﬁdel passage, one single sentence derogatory to Chris‑
tianity in the works of Thomas Hobbes of Malmesbury.
Have you, or have you not, read those works ? If you
have not read them, what right have you to say that they
are inﬁdel productions ? If you have read them, then
point out one inﬁdel passage in them, one single sentence
hostile to Christianity. I defy you to it. You have shrunk
from the attempt. You have indirectly acknowledged that
no such passages can be found in those works. Would it
not have been manly and courageous lo have acknowledged
your error—to have said that you had never read those
works, and that you had been misled with regard to them ?
Instead of doing this you have had recourse to subterfuge.
First, you have talked about Gibbon. Now tell me, acute
logician, able reasoner, what has Gibbon to do with Hobbes,
or Hobbes with Gibbon ? Two minds more dissimilar can
hardly be found than the philosopher of Malmesbury and
the historian of the Roman Empire. Would you, the lover
of knowledge, not only destroy the works of our greatest
dialectician, but the writings, likewise, of our greatest his‑
torian ? Would you consign to the same ﬂames the ‘ Le‑
viathan ' and the ‘ Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire ?'
Secondly, you have insinuated that some of Hobbes'
opinions lead to inﬁdelity. Prove it, I say. Now, I ask,
is there a single work renowned in science, in literature,
or in art, against which a similar charge has not been
brought by some narrow‐minded bigot? It is a well‑
known historical fact that every great discovery in astro‑
nomy, in natural history, in chemistry, or in any of the
physical sciences — that everything which has made us
better acquainted with the heavens, with the earth, and
with human nature—that every acquisition of knowledge
which has tended to elevate humanity, every attempt at
free inquiry, every eﬀort to shake oﬀ the trammels of au‑
thority, has been successively attacked by the ignorant and
narrow‐minded, as leading to inﬁdelity. Under this ma‑
lignant and accursed plea some of the greatest spirits of
the human race have been persecuted and slain. Socrates
was put to death as an inﬁdel ; he who ﬁrst said there were
Antipodes was burnt. The followers of Copernicus were
persecuted as disbelievers, and the great Galileo on bended
knees was compelled to assert that the earth was immov‑
able. Bacon and Descartes were taxed with irreligion ;
the doctrines of Locke were said to lead to materialism ;
Newton was accused of dethroning the Deity by the dis‑
covery of the law of gravitation ; a similar charge was made
against Franklin for explaining the nature of the thunder‑
bolt; Priestley's library was burnt and his person endan‑
gered on account of his religious opinions; and, in our own</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r44">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1471" y="383"/>
	<Point x="1472" y="514"/>
	<Point x="1467" y="785"/>
	<Point x="1466" y="1028"/>
	<Point x="1464" y="1048"/>
	<Point x="1463" y="1059"/>
	<Point x="1463" y="1066"/>
	<Point x="1462" y="1219"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="1266"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="1324"/>
	<Point x="1460" y="1337"/>
	<Point x="1459" y="1393"/>
	<Point x="1454" y="1628"/>
	<Point x="1451" y="1783"/>
	<Point x="1452" y="1790"/>
	<Point x="1450" y="1825"/>
	<Point x="1450" y="1904"/>
	<Point x="1446" y="2184"/>
	<Point x="1442" y="2253"/>
	<Point x="1442" y="2287"/>
	<Point x="1441" y="2348"/>
	<Point x="1442" y="2409"/>
	<Point x="1438" y="2547"/>
	<Point x="1431" y="2826"/>
	<Point x="1428" y="3107"/>
	<Point x="1421" y="3522"/>
	<Point x="1417" y="3801"/>
	<Point x="1413" y="3938"/>
	<Point x="1411" y="3966"/>
	<Point x="1409" y="4079"/>
	<Point x="1410" y="4104"/>
	<Point x="1407" y="4232"/>
	<Point x="1415" y="4231"/>
	<Point x="1416" y="4128"/>
	<Point x="1419" y="3940"/>
	<Point x="1425" y="3661"/>
	<Point x="1432" y="3245"/>
	<Point x="1436" y="2967"/>
	<Point x="1442" y="2688"/>
	<Point x="1449" y="2368"/>
	<Point x="1450" y="2247"/>
	<Point x="1456" y="1962"/>
	<Point x="1462" y="1547"/>
	<Point x="1466" y="1401"/>
	<Point x="1473" y="984"/>
	<Point x="1478" y="568"/>
	<Point x="1479" y="378"/>
	<Point x="1469" y="376"/>
	<Point x="1470" y="383"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r45" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1487" y="379"/>
	<Point x="1688" y="385"/>
	<Point x="1922" y="394"/>
	<Point x="2155" y="398"/>
	<Point x="2244" y="404"/>
	<Point x="2240" y="669"/>
	<Point x="2241" y="746"/>
	<Point x="2244" y="761"/>
	<Point x="2237" y="844"/>
	<Point x="2167" y="842"/>
	<Point x="2164" y="851"/>
	<Point x="2048" y="848"/>
	<Point x="1793" y="842"/>
	<Point x="1775" y="865"/>
	<Point x="1548" y="862"/>
	<Point x="1544" y="868"/>
	<Point x="1535" y="867"/>
	<Point x="1524" y="862"/>
	<Point x="1480" y="861"/>
	<Point x="1480" y="738"/>
	<Point x="1483" y="566"/>
	<Point x="1484" y="420"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>days, Buckland, Sedgwick, and the other geologists are
accused of overturning revelation by their discoveries with
regard to the past existence of the earth. In short, in all
ages, and amongst all nations, inﬁdelity has ever been the
war cry which the base, the ignorant, the intolerant, and
the canting tribe have raised against the great, the noble,
and the generous spirits of the human race. That cry you,
Mr Miall, have attempted to raise against the works which
I have edited. I now again solemnly call on you before
these, the electors of Southwark, whom you wish to repre‑
sent in Parliament—I challenge you to make good your
assertions. If you shrink from the attempt, or fail, as fail
you will, then I accuse you before your fellow‐citizens of
having brought this charge against me for base electioneer‑
ing purposes. I brand you as a calumniator, and appeal to
the poll of to‐morrow."</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r46" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1508" y="877"/>
	<Point x="2023" y="887"/>
	<Point x="2236" y="889"/>
	<Point x="2238" y="1017"/>
	<Point x="2140" y="1017"/>
	<Point x="2135" y="1025"/>
	<Point x="1868" y="1016"/>
	<Point x="1850" y="1040"/>
	<Point x="1818" y="1040"/>
	<Point x="1815" y="1045"/>
	<Point x="1477" y="1040"/>
	<Point x="1479" y="908"/>
	<Point x="1502" y="907"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The appeal was a most triumphant one. The election
took place on Thursday, and the result justiﬁed our ex‑
pectations : Sir William Molesworth was returned by an
overwhelming majority. At the close of the poll the
numbers were as follows :—</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TableRegion id="r47">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1571" y="1044"/>
	<Point x="1783" y="1048"/>
	<Point x="2149" y="1050"/>
	<Point x="2146" y="1147"/>
	<Point x="1568" y="1138"/></Coords></TableRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r48" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1477" y="1138"/>
	<Point x="1797" y="1148"/>
	<Point x="2081" y="1151"/>
	<Point x="2233" y="1157"/>
	<Point x="2233" y="1180"/>
	<Point x="1959" y="1180"/>
	<Point x="1956" y="1188"/>
	<Point x="1903" y="1186"/>
	<Point x="1898" y="1209"/>
	<Point x="1711" y="1207"/>
	<Point x="1709" y="1215"/>
	<Point x="1676" y="1212"/>
	<Point x="1668" y="1207"/>
	<Point x="1475" y="1205"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Sir William Molesworth therefore polled 413 votes more
than both his opponents united.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r49">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1719" y="1219"/>
	<Point x="1987" y="1222"/>
	<Point x="1987" y="1245"/>
	<Point x="1719" y="1241"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r50" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1953" y="1284"/>
	<Point x="1953" y="1250"/>
	<Point x="1758" y="1250"/>
	<Point x="1758" y="1284"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>IRELAND.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r51" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1498" y="1281"/>
	<Point x="1833" y="1289"/>
	<Point x="2233" y="1292"/>
	<Point x="2228" y="1515"/>
	<Point x="2225" y="1711"/>
	<Point x="2222" y="1848"/>
	<Point x="1975" y="1845"/>
	<Point x="1960" y="1879"/>
	<Point x="1805" y="1877"/>
	<Point x="1805" y="1884"/>
	<Point x="1793" y="1883"/>
	<Point x="1782" y="1877"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="1875"/>
	<Point x="1464" y="1684"/>
	<Point x="1468" y="1487"/>
	<Point x="1474" y="1312"/>
	<Point x="1497" y="1315"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE CONFLICT AT BALLINHASSIG.—Mr. O'Connell
has sent a subscription of twenty guineas towards the
relief of the friends and survivors of the persons who lost
their lives in the unhappy conﬂict at Ballinhassig. In
the letter to Mr Philip O'Connell, of Cork, which accom‑
panies the donation, Mr O'Connell states that, after the
fullest consideration of the verdict of the jurors who sat
on the inquest after the Ballinnhassig aﬀair, he has
arrived at the conclusion that he fears it is impossible to
disturb it. In reference to the conduct of the police he
says :—" 'Tis really shocking to think that the police
should be employed, with deadly weapons in their hands,
to decide upon the necessity of arresting persons not
guilty of felonious or capital oﬀences. It is a bad system
that sanctions the use of murderous weapons upon occa‑
sions where, even if the imputed crime of the slain were
really proved, the utmost punishment could not exceed
a small ﬁne or a short imprisonment."</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r52" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1495" y="1879"/>
	<Point x="1769" y="1883"/>
	<Point x="1780" y="1885"/>
	<Point x="1803" y="1887"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="1883"/>
	<Point x="2098" y="1887"/>
	<Point x="2222" y="1891"/>
	<Point x="2223" y="1933"/>
	<Point x="2220" y="2036"/>
	<Point x="2214" y="2237"/>
	<Point x="2210" y="2470"/>
	<Point x="2205" y="2739"/>
	<Point x="2199" y="3045"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="3333"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="3407"/>
	<Point x="2196" y="3418"/>
	<Point x="2196" y="3428"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="3436"/>
	<Point x="2190" y="3509"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="3518"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="3528"/>
	<Point x="2191" y="3540"/>
	<Point x="2183" y="3905"/>
	<Point x="2177" y="4247"/>
	<Point x="1947" y="4248"/>
	<Point x="1566" y="4244"/>
	<Point x="1420" y="4235"/>
	<Point x="1420" y="4218"/>
	<Point x="1424" y="3976"/>
	<Point x="1427" y="3779"/>
	<Point x="1432" y="3512"/>
	<Point x="1439" y="3099"/>
	<Point x="1442" y="2815"/>
	<Point x="1450" y="2534"/>
	<Point x="1458" y="2119"/>
	<Point x="1461" y="1900"/>
	<Point x="1492" y="1900"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>GREAT ORANGE DEMONSTRATION AT BELFAST.—
A grand Orange soiree was held in the Music Hall of
Belfast on the 4th inst., which was attended by about
1,000 persons, including Lord Roden, Colonel Verner,
Mr Watson, Mr Cleland, and other ultra‐Orangemen of
note. The hall was profusely hung with banners and
decorations strongly expressive of the political and reli‑
gious opinions of the assembly. When tea was over
Lord Roden was called to the chair, and the various
notables expressed their sentiments in terms of deep
sympathy for Mr Watson, and indignation at the conduct
of Government. The speech made by the noble chair‑
man at the close of the soiree contained some passages
which may be worth reproducing. Speaking of the act
which deprived Mr Watson of the commission of the
peace, he said, “ I cannot but think that it was an enor‑
mously harsh act of the Government to deprive such a man
of the commission of the peace ; and I cannot but think
that they themselves must feel that they have acted a
very inconsiderate part in degrading that individual, who,
in times of danger, acted with spirit in preserving the
peace of the country.” In reference to an observation
of Colonel Verner, who looked upon him (Lord Roden)
as the leader of the Protestants in Ireland, he said he
felt himself totally unworthy of the distinction, but added
he would give them all the assistance he could—a heart
truly devoted to the Protestant interest of Ireland. “ It
is now many years since ﬁrst I belonged to the Orange
Institution, and it was always my pride and happiness to
belong to that loyal body. It was in the vigour of youth,
when the body was active and the mind clear, that I
joined that body ; and I can say that, in 1836, the period
when that body was dissolved at the wish of the Sove‑
reign, its principles were nothing but loyalty to the Throne
and Constitution of Great Britain ; yes, loyalty to the
Crown of England was the great end and aim of those
institutions. I do not know whether it is a crime to re‑
organize them now or not—I won't say ; but that will
remain for those who know what is best to be done in
these trying times to the Protestant interests of the
country.” Whether it were merely “a singular coinci‑
dence,” or a concerted stratagem on the part of the
Orangemen, does not appear, but the fact of their having
adopted the Roden livery gave his lordship singular
pleasure :—“ I feel happy that you have chosen for your
colours orange and blue, to which you are so much at‑
tached. I am proud of that, for that happens to be the
colour of the very ancient livery (tremendous cheering) of
my own family.” As the livery of the House of Orleans
became the national colours of the French nation, so the
old coat of the Joscelyns now ﬂoats as the standard of
the Orangemen ; in the same manner the apron of the
blacksmith Gao was borne as the type of rebellion against
the tyrant Zohâk. Lord Roden continued—" I know
not whether it is a crime, but I don't think it culpable
that I should carry about my person the image of the
glorious William. (Kentish ﬁre.) I have done so for
many years, for two reasons. First, from my love and
aﬀection for the good and glorious man himself; and
next, from my love and gratitude for the man who gave
it to me, the Earl of Winchilsea. (Loud cheers and
Kentish ﬁre, in the midst of which his Lordship took
from his breast a miniature picture of the third William,
and exhibited it to the meeting amidst the most rapturous
applause). This I received from the Earl of Winchilsea
whose ancestor, the Earl of Nottingham, wore it during
the revolution of 1688 (cheers), as the personal friend o
our great deliverer. (Rounds of Kentish ﬁre.) I know
not whether that I am worthy to be deprived of the com‑
mission of the peace; but I do know that no persecution
will deter me from giving my zealous support to the good
cause," His Lordship conclude by stating, that in the</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r53">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2247" y="397"/>
	<Point x="2261" y="402"/>
	<Point x="2255" y="700"/>
	<Point x="2253" y="949"/>
	<Point x="2246" y="1366"/>
	<Point x="2238" y="1784"/>
	<Point x="2228" y="2198"/>
	<Point x="2222" y="2616"/>
	<Point x="2214" y="3048"/>
	<Point x="2205" y="3471"/>
	<Point x="2203" y="3748"/>
	<Point x="2193" y="4253"/>
	<Point x="2185" y="4253"/>
	<Point x="2184" y="4155"/>
	<Point x="2190" y="3876"/>
	<Point x="2193" y="3643"/>
	<Point x="2203" y="3091"/>
	<Point x="2213" y="2535"/>
	<Point x="2225" y="1979"/>
	<Point x="2236" y="1426"/>
	<Point x="2244" y="953"/>
	<Point x="2245" y="797"/>
	<Point x="2247" y="768"/>
	<Point x="2246" y="737"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r54" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2271" y="406"/>
	<Point x="2399" y="401"/>
	<Point x="2527" y="407"/>
	<Point x="3015" y="433"/>
	<Point x="3017" y="713"/>
	<Point x="2924" y="709"/>
	<Point x="2922" y="718"/>
	<Point x="2667" y="706"/>
	<Point x="2584" y="702"/>
	<Point x="2563" y="733"/>
	<Point x="2295" y="726"/>
	<Point x="2292" y="732"/>
	<Point x="2277" y="732"/>
	<Point x="2270" y="727"/>
	<Point x="2262" y="719"/>
	<Point x="2263" y="439"/>
	<Point x="2267" y="415"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>course of his life he was never present at any meeting
where he experienced more happiness than on the present
occasion.—The 'Dublin Warder,' a weekly Orange
journal, after referring to the Lisburn, Belfast, and other
demonstrations, says, "Preparations for other county
meetings are in progress, and ere the close of this month
the voice of Protestant Ireland will have declared to Peel
her immutable determination to resist his unjust and ill‑
timed attempts to stifﬂe the expression of independent
opinion in a free land.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r55" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2293" y="736"/>
	<Point x="2302" y="731"/>
	<Point x="2576" y="740"/>
	<Point x="2654" y="737"/>
	<Point x="2964" y="740"/>
	<Point x="3018" y="754"/>
	<Point x="3014" y="1169"/>
	<Point x="2979" y="1167"/>
	<Point x="2977" y="1174"/>
	<Point x="2771" y="1166"/>
	<Point x="2758" y="1185"/>
	<Point x="2743" y="1185"/>
	<Point x="2740" y="1196"/>
	<Point x="2734" y="1197"/>
	<Point x="2549" y="1193"/>
	<Point x="2545" y="1199"/>
	<Point x="2532" y="1199"/>
	<Point x="2523" y="1194"/>
	<Point x="2361" y="1188"/>
	<Point x="2352" y="1191"/>
	<Point x="2344" y="1191"/>
	<Point x="2332" y="1187"/>
	<Point x="2254" y="1187"/>
	<Point x="2258" y="903"/>
	<Point x="2262" y="766"/>
	<Point x="2284" y="759"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE NEW COLLEGES.—The ‘ Evening Packet,' the
organ of the Government, makes the following announce‑
ment:—“ We have reason to believe that the Government
is now occupied with the choice of individuals to ﬁll the
oﬃces of president and vice‐president of the new col‑
leges. In reply to applications made on their behalf,
candidates, we understand, are informed that no selection
has yet been made—that no engagements have been
entered into, nor assurances given—that the choice will
be determined solely by considerations of personal cha‑
racter and by moral and intellectual qualiﬁcations. It is
said that, in addition to apartments within the walls of
the college, the presidents will receive about 800l. per
annum, and the vice‐presidents 500l.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r56" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2291" y="1190"/>
	<Point x="2311" y="1191"/>
	<Point x="2319" y="1195"/>
	<Point x="2454" y="1201"/>
	<Point x="2462" y="1196"/>
	<Point x="2479" y="1197"/>
	<Point x="2487" y="1200"/>
	<Point x="2553" y="1205"/>
	<Point x="2693" y="1207"/>
	<Point x="2703" y="1202"/>
	<Point x="2719" y="1203"/>
	<Point x="2726" y="1205"/>
	<Point x="2870" y="1207"/>
	<Point x="2881" y="1202"/>
	<Point x="2897" y="1202"/>
	<Point x="2898" y="1208"/>
	<Point x="3009" y="1212"/>
	<Point x="3007" y="1268"/>
	<Point x="3006" y="1656"/>
	<Point x="2998" y="1953"/>
	<Point x="2992" y="2237"/>
	<Point x="2992" y="2380"/>
	<Point x="2983" y="2701"/>
	<Point x="2955" y="2704"/>
	<Point x="2711" y="2700"/>
	<Point x="2454" y="2696"/>
	<Point x="2366" y="2694"/>
	<Point x="2361" y="2710"/>
	<Point x="2348" y="2711"/>
	<Point x="2344" y="2722"/>
	<Point x="2246" y="2720"/>
	<Point x="2242" y="2727"/>
	<Point x="2225" y="2727"/>
	<Point x="2229" y="2541"/>
	<Point x="2235" y="2273"/>
	<Point x="2238" y="1994"/>
	<Point x="2245" y="1716"/>
	<Point x="2252" y="1300"/>
	<Point x="2254" y="1218"/>
	<Point x="2278" y="1213"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>ALARMING STATE OR THE COUNTY OF CAVAN.—
This county has been the theatre of great excitement
during the past week, in consequence of proposed de‑
monstrations, Catholic and Protestant, arising out of a
singular cause. The following statement from the ‘ Dub‑
lin Evening Pilot' will explain the case:—“ The friends
of Mr Robert Henry Southwell having formed a project
to raise from the Irish Catholics a sum of 55,000l. to re‑
purchase the Castle‐Hamilton estates for him, proclaimed
a meeting to be held at Killeshandra on the 8th (this
day), to give stability to the project ; meanwhile Mr
Southwell and the Rev. Dr Martin had an angry corre‑
spondence, which was made public. The Protestant party
announced a meeting on the same day, and determined
to take military possession of Killeshandra early on the
morning of the 8th, alleging that the meeting of the Ca‑
tholics was to commemorate and take revenge for the
battle of Ballynamuck (8th of September, 1798.) Terror
and confusion reigned through Cavan and Leitrim. Lord
Farnham, with a courage equal to the occasion, issued a
notice forbidding persons carrying arms to the meeting;
this was clearly aimed at the Orangemen. His lordship
has collected a great military force, cavalry and infantry,
and, after consulting with persons of all religious per‑
suasions, and having aﬃdavits as to an impending breach
of the peace, has issued a proclamation, the only course
which could prevent a regular battle. The Scots Greys,
from Dundalk, after a forced march, have just entered
Cavan, where there also have arrived a general oﬃcer
and Major Priestly, from Dublin. The county is, thank
God, ﬁlled with troops. Lord Farnham will be in Kil‑
leshandra with four regiments at an early hour ; so it is
to be hoped all will go oﬀ quietly.” Besides Lord Farn‑
ham's proclamation, the magistrates issued a notice cau‑
tioning all persons against attending either of the meet‑
ings. It is satisfactory to be able to state, that subsequent
accounts show that neither of the projected meetings took
place. The troops were all in readiness, but fortunately
there was no occasion for their services. The ‘ Dublin
Evening Post' says :—“ Our letters from Cavan state
that all passed oﬀ quietly. The Catholic clergy, from
their altars on Sunday, enforced the duty of obedience
to the law, and of avoiding all occasions of strife and
disturbance, and the result was, that the teetotallers, who
had abandoned their perfectly legal meeting and noble
purpose, aﬀorded no pretext for Orange violence or ag‑
gression.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r57" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2253" y="2724"/>
	<Point x="2510" y="2728"/>
	<Point x="2979" y="2733"/>
	<Point x="2978" y="2884"/>
	<Point x="2974" y="3137"/>
	<Point x="2966" y="3391"/>
	<Point x="2932" y="3390"/>
	<Point x="2736" y="3389"/>
	<Point x="2575" y="3390"/>
	<Point x="2531" y="3390"/>
	<Point x="2503" y="3388"/>
	<Point x="2353" y="3386"/>
	<Point x="2344" y="3415"/>
	<Point x="2211" y="3413"/>
	<Point x="2217" y="3110"/>
	<Point x="2223" y="2931"/>
	<Point x="2225" y="2754"/>
	<Point x="2245" y="2750"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>STATE OF THE HARVEST IN IRELAND.— Accounts
from various parts of the country convey the most gra‑
tifying assurances of the beneﬁcial eﬀects which the last
fortnight of ﬁne weather has had upon the crops. The
wheat has been partially injured—on that all are agreed ;
but the extent of surface sown last season, and the saving
inﬂuence of the present ﬁne weather, will yield and bring
to perfection at least an average crop. The oat crop is
peculiarly ﬁne in every part of the country, and will
yield an abundant produce. In the counties of Wicklow,
Wexford, Carlow, and Kildare, reaping has been in pro‑
gress during this week. In Meath, Westmeath, and far‑
ther north and west, the harvest is later ; but next week
extensive tracts of country will be ready for the sickle,
and the husbandman, we doubt not, will be amply re‑
warded, notwithstanding that the full measure of promise
which the month of June held forth will not be realised.
There has been a partial failure in the potato crop, but
only on lands adjacent to the coast. Generally, however,
this crop is excellent in quality, and the yield will be very
abundant.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r58" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2240" y="3418"/>
	<Point x="2410" y="3422"/>
	<Point x="2839" y="3418"/>
	<Point x="2968" y="3428"/>
	<Point x="2972" y="3496"/>
	<Point x="2964" y="3743"/>
	<Point x="2763" y="3745"/>
	<Point x="2755" y="3753"/>
	<Point x="2588" y="3750"/>
	<Point x="2514" y="3746"/>
	<Point x="2504" y="3775"/>
	<Point x="2207" y="3772"/>
	<Point x="2211" y="3515"/>
	<Point x="2213" y="3442"/>
	<Point x="2240" y="3433"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE GOVERNMENT AND THE ORANGE MAGISTRACY.
—Mr. Archdall, father of the member for Fermanagh,
who had been removed from the deputy‐lieutenancy of
that county, for attending the Orange meeting in Ennis‑
killen on the 12th ult., will also be deprived of the com‑
mission of the peace. It is rumoured that supersedeases
will soon be issued to the magistrates who attended at
Lisburn, but as a marquis of large possessions is num‑
bered amongst them, it may be doubted whether the Go‑
vernment will have the courage to apply their own rule
to the case of Lisburn.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r59">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2207" y="3783"/>
	<Point x="2418" y="3784"/>
	<Point x="2761" y="3784"/>
	<Point x="2957" y="3781"/>
	<Point x="2957" y="3804"/>
	<Point x="2949" y="3803"/>
	<Point x="2834" y="3806"/>
	<Point x="2626" y="3809"/>
	<Point x="2404" y="3806"/>
	<Point x="2206" y="3806"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r60" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2231" y="3810"/>
	<Point x="2473" y="3812"/>
	<Point x="2820" y="3814"/>
	<Point x="2959" y="3811"/>
	<Point x="2963" y="3853"/>
	<Point x="2951" y="4202"/>
	<Point x="2696" y="4208"/>
	<Point x="2680" y="4242"/>
	<Point x="2656" y="4245"/>
	<Point x="2197" y="4252"/>
	<Point x="2198" y="4146"/>
	<Point x="2205" y="3851"/>
	<Point x="2223" y="3846"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>VOTES OF THANKS FROM LLOYD'S.—At a general
meeting of the members of Lloyd's, held on Wednesday,
a special vote of thanks to his Majesty the King of Den‑
mark, for a valuable set of charts presented to the estab‑
lishment by order of his Majesty, and likewise to the
Royal Norwegian Finance Department at Christiania,
for the valuable charts of, and sailing directions for, the
north coast of Norway, presented by order of that depart‑
ment, was propose� and carried unanimously. The
honorary silver medal of Lloyd's to Lieutenant William
Gould, R.N., and votes of money to seamen instrumenta�
in saving the crews of vessels wrecked on the coast, were
proposed and carried at this meeting.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r30" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1598" y="281"/>
	<Point x="1643" y="281"/>
	<Point x="1643" y="282"/>
	<Point x="1688" y="282"/>
	<Point x="1688" y="283"/>
	<Point x="1733" y="283"/>
	<Point x="1733" y="284"/>
	<Point x="1778" y="284"/>
	<Point x="1778" y="285"/>
	<Point x="1823" y="285"/>
	<Point x="1823" y="286"/>
	<Point x="1868" y="286"/>
	<Point x="1868" y="287"/>
	<Point x="1913" y="287"/>
	<Point x="1913" y="288"/>
	<Point x="1958" y="288"/>
	<Point x="1958" y="289"/>
	<Point x="2003" y="289"/>
	<Point x="2003" y="290"/>
	<Point x="2048" y="290"/>
	<Point x="2048" y="291"/>
	<Point x="2093" y="291"/>
	<Point x="2093" y="292"/>
	<Point x="2138" y="292"/>
	<Point x="2138" y="293"/>
	<Point x="2183" y="293"/>
	<Point x="2183" y="296"/>
	<Point x="2184" y="296"/>
	<Point x="2184" y="299"/>
	<Point x="2185" y="299"/>
	<Point x="2185" y="302"/>
	<Point x="2186" y="302"/>
	<Point x="2186" y="305"/>
	<Point x="2187" y="305"/>
	<Point x="2187" y="308"/>
	<Point x="2188" y="308"/>
	<Point x="2188" y="311"/>
	<Point x="2189" y="311"/>
	<Point x="2189" y="314"/>
	<Point x="2190" y="314"/>
	<Point x="2190" y="316"/>
	<Point x="2191" y="316"/>
	<Point x="2191" y="319"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="319"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="322"/>
	<Point x="2193" y="322"/>
	<Point x="2193" y="325"/>
	<Point x="2194" y="325"/>
	<Point x="2194" y="328"/>
	<Point x="2195" y="328"/>
	<Point x="2195" y="331"/>
	<Point x="2196" y="331"/>
	<Point x="2196" y="334"/>
	<Point x="2197" y="334"/>
	<Point x="2197" y="336"/>
	<Point x="2198" y="336"/>
	<Point x="2196" y="336"/>
	<Point x="2196" y="337"/>
	<Point x="2195" y="337"/>
	<Point x="2195" y="338"/>
	<Point x="2194" y="338"/>
	<Point x="2194" y="339"/>
	<Point x="2193" y="339"/>
	<Point x="2193" y="340"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="340"/>
	<Point x="2192" y="341"/>
	<Point x="2191" y="341"/>
	<Point x="2191" y="342"/>
	<Point x="2190" y="342"/>
	<Point x="2190" y="343"/>
	<Point x="2189" y="343"/>
	<Point x="2189" y="344"/>
	<Point x="2189" y="343"/>
	<Point x="2160" y="343"/>
	<Point x="2160" y="342"/>
	<Point x="2132" y="342"/>
	<Point x="2132" y="341"/>
	<Point x="2085" y="341"/>
	<Point x="2085" y="340"/>
	<Point x="2038" y="340"/>
	<Point x="2038" y="339"/>
	<Point x="1991" y="339"/>
	<Point x="1991" y="338"/>
	<Point x="1944" y="338"/>
	<Point x="1944" y="337"/>
	<Point x="1897" y="337"/>
	<Point x="1897" y="336"/>
	<Point x="1850" y="336"/>
	<Point x="1850" y="335"/>
	<Point x="1803" y="335"/>
	<Point x="1803" y="334"/>
	<Point x="1767" y="334"/>
	<Point x="1767" y="333"/>
	<Point x="1731" y="333"/>
	<Point x="1731" y="332"/>
	<Point x="1695" y="332"/>
	<Point x="1695" y="331"/>
	<Point x="1660" y="331"/>
	<Point x="1660" y="330"/>
	<Point x="1624" y="330"/>
	<Point x="1624" y="329"/>
	<Point x="1588" y="329"/>
	<Point x="1588" y="328"/>
	<Point x="1548" y="328"/>
	<Point x="1548" y="326"/>
	<Point x="1549" y="326"/>
	<Point x="1549" y="318"/>
	<Point x="1550" y="318"/>
	<Point x="1550" y="310"/>
	<Point x="1551" y="310"/>
	<Point x="1551" y="302"/>
	<Point x="1552" y="302"/>
	<Point x="1552" y="295"/>
	<Point x="1553" y="295"/>
	<Point x="1553" y="287"/>
	<Point x="1554" y="287"/>
	<Point x="1554" y="281"/>
	<Point x="1598" y="281"/>
	<Point x="1598" y="280"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE EXAMINER.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r34" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="894" y="285"/>
	<Point x="894" y="302"/>
	<Point x="895" y="302"/>
	<Point x="895" y="320"/>
	<Point x="896" y="320"/>
	<Point x="896" y="331"/>
	<Point x="895" y="331"/>
	<Point x="895" y="345"/>
	<Point x="870" y="345"/>
	<Point x="870" y="344"/>
	<Point x="868" y="344"/>
	<Point x="868" y="343"/>
	<Point x="867" y="343"/>
	<Point x="867" y="342"/>
	<Point x="865" y="342"/>
	<Point x="865" y="341"/>
	<Point x="864" y="341"/>
	<Point x="864" y="340"/>
	<Point x="862" y="340"/>
	<Point x="862" y="339"/>
	<Point x="861" y="339"/>
	<Point x="861" y="338"/>
	<Point x="859" y="338"/>
	<Point x="859" y="337"/>
	<Point x="858" y="337"/>
	<Point x="858" y="336"/>
	<Point x="856" y="336"/>
	<Point x="856" y="335"/>
	<Point x="817" y="335"/>
	<Point x="817" y="336"/>
	<Point x="780" y="336"/>
	<Point x="780" y="337"/>
	<Point x="743" y="337"/>
	<Point x="743" y="338"/>
	<Point x="743" y="290"/>
	<Point x="773" y="290"/>
	<Point x="773" y="289"/>
	<Point x="803" y="289"/>
	<Point x="803" y="288"/>
	<Point x="833" y="288"/>
	<Point x="833" y="287"/>
	<Point x="863" y="287"/>
	<Point x="863" y="286"/>
	<Point x="893" y="286"/>
	<Point x="893" y="285"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>1845.]</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
